JOSHUA PETERS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



(320)293-1372 in PETERS-L-JOSHUA 👩 JOSHUALPETERS



PETERS.L.JOSHUA@GMAIL.COM

Experienced business owner with a strong background in marketing applications, collaborating with indie developers, AAA publishers, and startups across the globe. The past five years I've grown as a Sole Proprietor but I am excited to transition into the professional tech industry working with a team.

CORE SKILLS

JAVA SE HTML MYSOL CSS SPRING BOOT JAVASCRIPT JAVA EE FRAMEWORK JQUERY BOOTSTRAP **OBJECT ORIENTED** VCS WITH GIT THYMELEAF PAIRED PARTNER **PROGRAMMING**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TWITCH TV Partnered Broadcaster

2014 - 2019

Produced, scheduled, and broadcasted video content to a remote website on a weekly or daily basis. Analyzed audience retention data and viewer trends to produce targeted content, and changed content to reflect audience demands. Worked directly with developers providing player feedback to help shape the future of the game and to solve existing problems.

VERIZON WIRELESS CSR / RSR

2007 - 2008

Harnessed initiative and resourcefulness to generate additional revenue by leveraging strong interpersonal skills and communication to up-sell during point of sale. Promoted to a sales position from customer service after a year of hire from excellent performance and exceeding all metrics.

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

US AIR FORCE Maintenance Journeyman

2009 - 2014

Fully trained in Aerospace Ground Equipment (AGE) and Precision Measurement Equipment Laboratory (PMEL). Deployed to Ali Al Saleem Air Force Base and supported mission Iraqi Freedom. Diligent driver dispatched 200+ units; lauded by flight-line expediters. 100% completion on all quality assurance tests. Graduated basic training as an honor graduate.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

COFFEE SHOP

OCT 2019

Developed search capabilities to interact with website and iterated through data structures primarily of which were arrays. Designed a professional product using Bootstrap Grid and used DOM to dynamically update the page upon interaction.

WEATHER MAP

OCT 2019

Learned how to use Mapbox and Darksky APIs and developed an interactive weather map for any known address. Wrote javaScript code so both APIs work in parallel and build a working software program from scratch alone.

MOVIE LIST

NOV 2019

Initialized JSON database to load into the site with ajax. On page load generates HTML from JSON responses. Iterated through a complex API to retrieve specific information. Merged to Github while rotating with paired partner programming.

PERSONAL WEBSITE

NOV 2019

A fully built website summarizing all projects and job history. Used bootstrap, HTML, and CSS to publish site on github. You can view the site here: joshualpeters.github.io

ADLISTER

JAN 2019

A full-stack application with developed functionality to navigate a database. Used MVC coding patterns to organize code with CRUD capabilities.

CAPSTONE

FEB 2019

The final project from the Codeup program. A full-stack application created by 3-4 students with real-world application. Projects are demonstrated at the end of February at Codeup.

EDUCATION HISTORY

CODEUP

SEPT 2019

A fully-immersive, project based, and intensive 20 week full stack Java career accelerator that provides students with 600+ hours of expert instruction in software development.